

I am an experienced teacher of 15 years, currently completing a program pursuing a Colorado elementary teaching license with the Friends Teacher Preparation Program. I am dedicated to building inclusive and equitable relationships with students, parents, and colleagues to create an engaging and collaborative learning environment that contributes to each child's success.

# **Professional Experience**

## **Boulder Country Day School** Gunbarrel. CO

Teacher Candidate – Friends School Teacher Preparation Program

Aug 2018 – May 2019

- One year of classroom experience in elementary education.
- Planned and implemented a thematic unit about the Boulder County Watershed.
- Use reflective analysis of instructional strategies to create intentional and engaging lessons, creating interactive learning opportunities for each child.
- Collaborate with colleagues on student projects.

#### Treehouse Learning, LLC

Louisville, CO

Lead Teacher & Preschool Lead Aug 2009 – July 2018

- Experienced teacher with an average of 27 students.
- Research, design, and implement innovative and engaging lesson plans and activities that develop intellectual, physical, and social/emotional learning.
- Successfully improve student participation in the classroom through integration of creative role-playing exercises.
- Successfully reduced student behavior issues by establishing a strong teamwork environment.
- Explore and implement project-based learning that allows students to become better self-learners.
- Plan, implement, monitor, and assess student development through individual observations and documentation.
- In two months, increased literacy skills of Pre-K students to 90% of children recognizing all letters of the alphabet and 50% of children knowing all letter sounds.
- Created individualized goal sheets to differentiate and scaffold children's learning and document progress.
- Develop reciprocal, culturally responsive relationships with families and community to improve communication and trust between teachers, students, and parents.
- Track and meet yearly continuing education guidelines to implement new knowledge in the classroom setting.
- Analyzed Colorado Academic Standards (CAS) in order to create and develop child assessment forms.
- Act as a liaison between teaching teams and administration to maintain policies, solve problems, and improve curriculum.
- Train and mentor diverse teaching teams with successful outcomes in classroom management, behavior management, and curriculum focused strategies.

## Peace of Mind Early Education

Woodbury, MN

Lead Teacher & Program Coordinator Sep 2000 – Apr 2001, July 2001 – Oct 2002, Sep 2005 – Aug 2009

- Set up individualized learning plans for students in a mixed age classroom (3 to 5-year-olds).
- Knowledge of human behavior and performance, individual differences in ability, personality, and interests, using different learning styles for student achievement.
- Experience implementing and evaluating assessments while tracking progress using verbal and written communication and formalized recording methods for semiannual parent/teacher conferences.
- Successful in collaborative design, implementation, and supervision of developmentally appropriate program including day-to-day operation and curriculum, field trips, and special events.
- Achieved team mentor status; training and guiding team members in the classroom.
- Schedule and conduct tours of the school for families interested in enrolling.

#### Hillsborough Kids Inc.

Family Services Counselor & Care Manager
Oct 2002 – Aug 2005

Tampa, FL

- Crisis intervention, counseling, and protective supervision for children and families.
- Researched, developed, and implemented case plans for families in the child welfare system.
- Coordinated meetings and therapy for families; supervise parent/child visits.
- Attended and participated in court hearings regarding family progress on case plans.
- Observed and recorded behaviors of children and families for use in court document writings and hearings.
- Facilitated adoptions and foster care services.
- Supervise the health and well-being of at-risk children (ages 0-18) in families and residential facilities.
- Mentored positive choices and appropriate communication and behavioral interaction among children and families.
- Fostered partnerships among children, parents, and the community.

#### **Developmental Learning Center**

Assistant Teacher

St. Thomas, U.S. Virgin Islands

Apr 2001 - Jul 2001

## **Education**

B.A. Psychology (2000)

University of Wisconsin–Stout

Colorado Early Childhood Teacher Qualification (2010)

Front Range Community College

Yoga Alliance Certified Yoga Teacher (2018)

Breathe for Change–Denver

SMART-1 (Stress Management and Relaxation Techniques in Education) (2018)

Colorado State University

Colorado Initial Teacher License (June 2019)

Friends Teacher Preparation Program

M.A. Learning, Developmental and Family Sciences (expected August 2020)

University of Colorado-Denver

Concentration in Human Learning and Development